# Adrian Monteil, BS

## FULL STACK DEVELOPER, JAVASCRIPT ENTHUSIAST.

#### **PROFILE**

I spent 10 years in the automation industry and I decided to orient my career towards web development. After 2 years of freelancing and bulding my skills I am now well versed with the following technologies and concepts:

- React.js
- Vue.js
- Node.js
- MongoDB
- PostgreSQL
- Rest API
- OOP
- Docker
- SSR
- PWA
- GIT/GITHUB
- Data Structures

## **PERSONAL DETAILS**

#### **Address**

West Palm Beach, Florida

## CONTACT

- monteiladrian@gmail.com
- 347 325 1581
- o adrianmonteil1983.github.io/resume/
- inkedin.com/in/adrianmonteil

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## Fullstack developer/smart building integrator

#### SMART AUT HOMATION

2018 - Ongoing

2017 - 2017

- Developed an open platform for smart home using react.js, node.js, mongoDB to avoid expensive proprietary solutions.
- Used socket.io and low level socket with node.js for real time hardware communication.
- Used REST API to fetch data on the internet. (weather, location).
- Reverse engineer to integrate communication protocols using wireshark.
- Integrated automation, multi room, AV, hardware to improve security, comfort and energy saving in houses and buildings.

# Project manager smart building

TIL TECHNOLOGIES

- In charge of large national projects (+400Ke) for smart buildings and electronic security
- Quotations.
- Technical support for sales team.
- Studied and realized complex architecture (3rd party integrations, database communication, network architectures)

## International field manager / project managment

**AXIOME CONCEPT** 2014 - 2017

- Designed, programmed, commissioned complex hardware and SCADA architecture for smart building in france and in Qatar.
- Participed in large national projects, +500Ke, Indigo parkings, DOHA airport, DOHA SHERATON,
  LUSAIL MARINA. centralisation in one hypersion software to control cctv, intercom, lighting system,
  technical alarms, hvac, parking payment system, etc...
- Developed python scripts to reduce configuration time (80% time saved).
- Managed local teams of technicians (10 people).
- Participated in technical meetings with clients.
- Designed IT and industrial networks to be able to centralize every system.
- Used of network tools such as wireshark, and linux command line.
- In charge of Low voltage wiring verifications.

#### Developer

HERVE THERMIQUE 2013 -2014

- Developed softwares using C sharp and VB script (OPC client, Time server).
- Used wiresharp for reverse engineering.
- Developed PLC programming using Pascal language (structured text).
- Used gateway softwares such as kepware.
- Used different communication protocols (OPC, modbus, TCP/IP, bacnet).

## Field engineer smart building

VARIOUS COMPANIES 2003 - 2013

- Programming and configuring smart building softwares and hardware.
- Technical support for smart building softwares, IP CCTV, Alarm system, acces control, IP intercom.
- High security sites (prisons, stadiums, military).
- Technical trainner for technicians.

## EDUCATION

# Intensive trainning web development

UDEMY 2018 - 2020

ESL

NEW YORK ENGLISH CENTER 2018 - 2019

Bachelor degree computer engineering

UNIVERSITY OF BORDEAUX 1 2014

CCNA 1 & CCNA2(routing & switching)

CISCO 2009

Trade school former electrician

LEP SUD GIRONDE 2003